Ahmet Taşcı

Oracle ERP Technical Consultant / Backend Developer

Ahmet is a technical consultant and solutions architect with experience of more than 10 years in Oracle ERP field. Accomplished lots of projects with his teammates by listening customer needs, analyzing, designing, developing, testing and deploying.

Ahmet is also learning new skills of web development technologies and started to implement backend side already. Very enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success.

Work History

Current

Current

Current

2022-02 - Frontend Developer

Natica IT Consulting, Istanbul, Turkey

- Knowledge on HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap4.
- Just starting to a Udemy course on React framework.
- Preparing myself for development of a modern responsive web application, a payment system for FMCG (Fast Moving Consumer Goods) companies.

2021-12 - Backend Developer

Natica IT Consulting, Istanbul, Turkey

- Continuing company start up project which will include web and mobile apps.
- Developing backend architecture: Designing database on PostgreSQL, developing middleware web services using Python Flask Restfull framework, orchestrating backend with Nginx reverse proxy and uWSGI web server on Ubuntu Linux server.
- Assisting business process operations and user interface design to functional team.

2018-06 - ERP Senior Technical Consultant

- Oracle EBS R12.2.9 Re-Implementation Project:
- Fresh setup and implementation project of EBS R12.2.9 and database 19c.
- Custom database design and standard data

Contact

Address

Kartal, Istanbul, 34, 34882

Phone

542 525 1139

E-mail

tr.ahmettasci@gmail.com

Skills

SQL



PL/SQL

••••

Excellent

Oracle Foms

••••• Excellent

Oracle Workflow

•••••

Excellent

Oracle Reports

Excellent

Oracle Discoverer

••••• Excellent

Oracle ICS

Very Good

Python



Agesa (Avivasa), Istanbul, Turkey

migration from old system to new system.

- Providing end to end run of data integrations between core system and third parties which includes file transfers and web services.
- Oracle R12 Treasury Implementation and Integration Project:
- Oracle treasury module setup on R12 system. Also integration projects implemented between Oracle system and portfolio management companies.
- Cash Flow Management Project:
- Integration project between Oracle system and cash flow management company. Implementation of web services using Oracle Integrated SOA Gateway module.

2014-11 - Senior Consultant, Solution Architect, Team 2022-02 Leader

Teknosa, Istanbul, Turkey

- Worked with customers or prospective customers to develop integrated solutions and lead detailed architectural dialogues to facilitate delivery of comprehensive solution.
- Guided and influenced existing partners on recommended upgrades and enhancements to integrated solutions.
- Built strong relationships with customers through positive attitude and attentive response.
- Full support and development over Replenishment,
 Allocation and EBS integrations over RMS
 applications and database.
- Carrefoursa Shop in Shop Store System: Consigned sales model integration of Teknosa goods to Carrefoursa customers. Project consist of inventory, pricing, sales and invoice management which based on custom setup and data integrations.
- Serial Number Tracking System: Transition from quantity based inventory management system to serial number specific inventory tracking system.
- Inter-Org Transfer Systems: Development and maintenance of internal requisitions and internal orders among stores. Inventory push systems from central warehouse to stores.

Very Good

PostgreSQL



Oracle DB



HTML



CSS



Languages

English



- Smart Price Lists: Managing price lists with smart rules, including UI design, database design, importing and exporting xls files properties and workflow approval mechanism.
- Assortment: Item-Store based automatic assortment system that determines which items can be transferred to which stores. The result set of system applied to all inventory transfer systems.
- Special Price: System for stores to get extra discount by approval of their managers on specific items in order to attract more customers.
- Several other Oracle forms, Oracle Discoverer reports, Oracle workflow, Oracle reports and Data Integration developments and reinforcements depending on modules Sales Order Management, Pricing, Purchase Order Management, Inventory Management and iProcurement Portal.
- Oracle Retail Merchandising System (RMS): Full support, maintenance and development of RMS, Allocation and Replenishment transfer systems.

2019-09 - Oracle ICS Developer

2019-12

İş Bankası, İstanbul, Türkey

- Oracle Procurement Cloud Data Integration Project:
- Inside the scope of Oracle Procurement Cloud implementation project, several middleware data integrations built using Oracle ICS product.

2019-01 - ICM Cloud Integration Developer 2019-09

Anadolu Sigorta, Istanbul, Turkey

- Oracle ICM Cloud Data Integration Projects
- Staging Project: Integration project between main premium systems and Oracle ICM Cloud system.
 Data taken from premium systems over ETL tool into a custom Oracle database. Controlled and reformed on custom database. Then final files produced to upload Oracle ICM system using Oracle Content Management system.
- Hierarchy Synchronization Project: Premium hierarchies of company are holding on both user file systems and Oracle ICM Cloud system. Up to date

hierarchies taken from user files with ETL tool on a custom Oracle database. Also previous version taken from ICM cloud with Oracle BI reports. Then after comparison, old hierarchies are deleted and new hierarchies created on Oracle ICM system with calling Oracle ICM Cloud web services on custom database.

2012-01 - ERP Technical Consultant

2014-01

2011-12

Daikin, Istanbul, Turkey

- Led projects and analyzed data to identify opportunities for improvement.
- Quickly learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks, improving efficiency and productivity.
- DBS: Data integration and automation project with 9 banks, includes sending of AR invoices to the banks, receiving and applying customer sales guarantees, receiving cash receipts and applying them to the invoices, which depends on text file transfers on FTP/SFTP network protocol.
- GAIN: Data integration project, sending several types of company data including daily sales results, customer info, inventory data, product info and order data to any specific server as text files.
- Check, Debenture and Bank Statement Integration:
 Receiving check and debenture records as text files
 from specific banks and creating cash receipts on
 ERP system. Clearing them via bank statements
 receiving from banks in MT940 file format using
 FTP/SFTP file protocol.
- Several Oracle forms, Oracle BI reports, Oracle reports and Oracle workflow developments and reinforcements depending on modules Receivables, Payables, General Ledger, Cash Management, Treasury, Sales, Shipping, Pricing, Purchasing, Inventory, Human Resources and Alerts.

2011-09 - ERP Junior Technical Consultant

Ülker, Istanbul, Turkey

- Oracle R12 iSupplier Portal Setup
- Developing custom jsf pages using Oracle application framework

Education

2004-09 - Bachelor of Science: Computer And Educational Technologies

Boğaziçi University - Istanbul